Finding Aid for Frank G. Millard Papers, 1904-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Frank G. Millard Papers 1904-1976
Millard, Frank G. (Frank Gurnee), 1897-1976.
85341 Aa 2 AC
Republican attorney general of Michigan, 1951-1954, general counsel of the Department of the Army. World War I letters, papers detailing work as chairman of the committee on emerging problems of the Michigan Constitutional Convention; miscellaneous genealogical material, and diaries and memoranda books; scrapbooks concerning political career, especially his service as state attorney general; and photographs.
4 linear feet in 6 boxes
7 oversize volumes
1 phonograph records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Mr. and Mrs. Frank G. Millard (donor 5512 ) in three accessions in 1974, 1977, and 1979.
The collection is open to research.
Frank Gurnee Millard was born March 1, 1897 in Corunna, Michigan. He received his primary and high school education in Corunna. Subsequently he attended the University of Michigan, from which he received a bachelor's degree in 1914 and a law degree in 1916.
Millard practiced law in Flint. In addition he was active in Republican Party affairs. He chaired the Genesee County Republican Committee from 1922 until 1924, and again in 1940. From 1948 until 1950 he sat on the Republican State Central Committee.
Millard was elected the state's attorney general in 1950, a post he held until 1954. In 1955 he went to Washington where he was appointed general counsel of the Department of the Army. In 1961 he returned to Michigan and was elected a delegate to the state constitutional convention. At the convention he chaired the Committee on Emerging Problems.
Millard's career in law and politics was interrupted by repeated military service. During the First World War he saw action as an artillery lieutenant in France. In 1921 he helped organize the Michigan National Guard, which he remained active in until 1952. Millard also served in the armed forces during World War II. Frank Millard died in November 1976.
Only a few papers survived Millard. Correspondence, most interesting for his letters written in France during 1917, and a small body of papers from his committee chairmanship at the 1961 state constitutional convention, highlight the collection. A large number of newspaper clippings about his career, and many awards and citations he received, are also available. A few items regarding his military career, his political activities and his membership in the Masons can also be found.
A large number of photographs and albums are also found in the collection. Included are five scrapbooks, 1955-1961, covering the period when Frank Millard was general counsel in the Department of the Army. These scrapbooks are 70-80 percent photographic, and the remainder consist of clippings, programs, correspondence, schedules and itineraries. Another scrapbook covers the years 1912-1914 when Millard was a student at the University of Michigan. It also contains three pages of earlier material dated 1901-1910. This scrapbook is more than half photographic in content with the rest consisting of programs, clippings, and memorabilia.
Subjects:
Michigan. Dept. of Attorney General.; Michigan. Constitutional Convention (1961-1962); Michigan--Politics and government--1939-1945.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Millard, Frank G. (Frank Gurnee), 1897-1976.; Republican Party (Mich.); United States. Army.; United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; World War, 1914-1918.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Archons (University of Michigan); Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Business enterprises.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Corunna.; Camp Grayling (Mich.); Children.; Corunna (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Corunna High School (Mich.); Flint (Mich.); Post office buildings--Michigan--Flint.; Streets--Michigan--Flint.; France.; Freemasonry.; Griffins (University of Michigan); Interiors.; Machine shops.; McCorkell family.; Michigamua.; Michigan. Dept. of Attorney General.; Michigan. Constitutional Convention (1961-1962); Michigan. National Guard.; Military art and science.; Millard, Dorothy McCorkell.; Millard, Frank A.; Millard, Frank G. (Frank Gurnee), 1897-1976.; Millard family.; Parades and processions.; Politics and government--1946-1960.; Post offices--Michigan--Flint.; Republican Party (Mich.); Soldiers--American.; Sports.; Stables.; Streets--Michigan--Flint.; Summerfield, Arthur Ellsworth, 1899-1972.; United States. Army.; University of Michigan--Sports.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945.
Genre Terms:
Albums.; Diaries.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Personal/Activities
  - Genealogical material, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Diaries and memoranda books, 1918, 1958, 1964 (Box 1)
    (also includes 1879 diary of family member)
  - Correspondence
    - Undated (Box 1)
    - 1904-June 1918 (Box 1)
    - July-December 1918 (Box 1)
    - 1919 (Box 1)
    - 1920-1960 (Box 1)
    - 1961-1969 (Box 1)
    - 1970-1974 (Box 1)
  - State Constitutional Convention
    - Committee on Emerging Problems
      - Agendas and index (Box 1)
      - Subcommittee 1: Pensions (Box 1)
      - Subcommittee 2, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Subcommittee 3, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Subcommittee 4: Intergovernmental relations, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Masons (Box 1)
  - Military service (Box 1)
  - Political material (Box 1)
  - Awards and citations, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Sound recordings
  - Millard receiving Distinguished Civilian Service award April 1, 1955, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes (Box 1)
  - Tenth Anniversary, Army General Counsel July 26, 1960, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes (Box 1)
  - "Pentagonitis," by Lt. Col. Truman F. Cook, military assistant to Millard, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes (Box 1)
  - "S/A presentation to Mr. Millard", 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes (Box 1)
  - Heritage Day address before Genesee County Historical and Museum Society May 21, 1974, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes (Box 1)
    (Requires permission of WFDF radio for any rebroadcast)
  - Flint, Michigan post office ground breaking ceremony, 33 1/3 rpm phonorecord (Box 1)
    (sound track accompanying film no. 8, described below with films; shelved separately)
- Visual Materials
  - Photographs
    - Army General Counsel
      (see also oversize box 6)
      - Armed Forces Day speech 1955 (Box 2)
      - Secretarial Alumni Conference
        - 1966 (Box 2)
        - 1967 (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Attorney General
      - Mackinac Island meetings (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
        (includes photo of 1954 Lansing HUAC hearing)
    - Constitutional Convention (Box 2)
    - Corunna High School (Box 2)
      (includes photos of athletic teams and reunion)
    - Corunna scenes (Box 2)
      (includes photos of Millard store and home, and livery barn)
    - Flint scenes (Box 2)
      (includes photos of street scenes with arches and school group)
    - McCorkell family (Box 2)
    - McCorkell machine shop, Flint (Box 2)
    - Masonic (Box 2)
    - Michigan National Guard (Box 2)
      (includes photos of Memorial Day parade in Flint and camp at Grayling)
    - Michigan politics (Box 2)
    - Millard, Dorothy McCorkell (Box 2)
    - Millard, Frank A. (Box 2)
    - Millard, Frank G.
      - Portraits as a child (Box 2)
      - Portraits as a young man (Box 2)
      - Portraits as an older man (Box 2)
    - Millard, Frank G. and Dorothy M. (Box 2)
    - Millard family and friends, most unidentified (Box 2)
    - Portraits of others inscribed to Millard (Box 2)
    - Summerfield, Arthur E. (Box 2)
    - University of Michigan (Box 2)
      (includes Frank and Dorothy Millard photos)
    - World War I
      - Album (Box 2)
      - Photos (Box 2)
        (includes some unidentified photos that may be post-war Michigan National Guard)
    - World War II (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Albums
    - Reception for Arthur E. Summerfield and Inaugural Ball 1957, 2 volumes (Box 2)
    - Visit to Hawaii 1958 (Box 2)
    - Visit to Okinawa 1959 (Box 2)
    - Knights Templar meeting honoring Frank G. Millard 1965 (Box 2)
    - 1955-1956 (Volume 1)
      (Vol. 1 includes earlier photos: Lambda Phi sorority, National Guard, 1952 Eisenhower campaign appearance; includes personal photos and photos relating to service as Army General Counsel)
    - 1956-1958 (Volume 2)
      (Vol. 2 includes personal photos and photos relating to service as Army General Counsel)
    - 1958-1959 (Volume 3)
      (Vol. 3 includes personal photos (some Knights Templar photos) and photos relating to service as Army General Counsel)
    - 1959-1960 (Volume 4)
      (Vol. 4 includes personal photos (some Knights Templars photos) and photos relating to service as Army General Counsel)
    - 1960-1961 (Volume 5)
      (Vol. 5 includes personal photos and photos relating to service as Army General Counsel)
  - Oversize Photographs (Box 6)
    (include photos of Army Policy Council, Genesee County Bar Association, Masons, Michigamua, Michigan National Guard, Portraits as an older man, Portraits of others inscribed to Millard, and World War I)
  - Films
    (tentative identifications only)
    - Hamilton Field, roses, Fresno, 8mm color (Box 3)
      (film no. 1)
    - Florida, Virginia, 16mm black and white silent (Box 3)
      (film no. 2)
    - Rodeo, adobe, grapes, 8mm color (Box 3)
      (film no. 3)
    - Lamb derby, Lake Tahoe, 8mm color (Box 3)
      (film no. 4)
    - Millard family reel, 16mm black and white silent (Box 3)
      (film no. 5)
    - Hammer Field with Col. Kirkney, Colorado, Dressers Mountain House, 8mm color (Box 3)
      (film no. 6)
    - Camp McCoy, Lake Charlevoix, Mardi Gras, 16mm black and white silent (Box 3)
      (film no. 7)
    - Flint, Michigan post office ground breaking ceremony, 16mm black and white silent (Box 3)
      (film no. 8, with accompanying sound track on phonorecord, described above with sound recordings)
    - Fort Benning, 16mm black and white silent (Box 3)
      (film no. 9)
    - Home movies, 8mm color
      - 1957 (Box 3)
        (film nos. 10-11)
      - 1953 (Box 3)
        (film nos. 12-13)
- Scrapbooks
  - 1900-1916 (Box 4)
    (includes photos and memorabilia of Corunna High School and University of Michigan athletics, Griffins, Archons, and Michigamua)
  - 1930-1940 (Box 4)
    (includes clippings and photos relating to Michigan National Guard)
  - 1941-1945 (Box 5)
    (relates to World War II service in California)
  - 1950-1952 (Volume 6)
    (clippings relating to service as Attorney General)
  - 1953-1954 (Volume 7)